# Christian Provido

Front-end Web Developer

# **Personal Info**

#### **Address**

Moonwalk Subd. Talon 5 Las-Pinas City, Metro Manila, PH

## Skype and Slack

provido.calbert@gmail.com

### E-mail

provido.calbert@gmail.com

#### **WWW**

battlecheeze.github.ic

## LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/calbertprovido

## Github

https://github.com/battlecheeze

# **Soft Skills**

Communication

Advanced

Collaboration

Advanced

# Hard skills

**GIMP/Photoshop** 

Advanced

HTML/CSS

Advanced

**JavaScript** 

Intermediate

Accomplished front-end and email developer motivated by challenging projects and fresh ideas. Extensive experience designing & building websites (using HTML5, CSS3 and various web scripting technologies) as well as responsive emails compatible in over 30+ email clients.

## Experience

## 2019-05 - Present

## **ITMishelle**

- Freelance Front End Developer support on contract basis
- Coordinating with Japanese clients and various small businesses to finalize designs and confirm requirements
- Creating custom mockups and developing intuitive UIs and Designing responsive webpages with accessibility standards in mind
- Testing frontend code in multiple browsers to ensure cross-browser compatibility

#### 2018-01 - Present

# **The Defence Works**

- Customise responsive cross-browser compatible landing pages using HTML(5), CSS(3), JS and jQuery
- Optimise & hand coded 90% of training emails and newsletters for custom events compatible in over 30+ email clients
- · Test and troubleshoot HTML emails using Litmus.
- Worked as a Virtual Assistant and Lead Generation Specialist

#### 2014-10 - 2017-09

## **Innodata**

Data Researcher and Analyst For Mediamiser, Vuelio and AgilityPR Project

## 2008-07 - 2012-08

# SPi Global

 Worked as Content Editor that handle responsibilities of on-time loading pages and contents of caselaw documents for LexisNexis Account

## Education

2013-01 - 2013-02

# <u>Tekguru</u>

 Training Comptia A+ Essentials 2009 Objectives with Practical Application

## 2002 - 2008

# **AMA College of Las Pinas**

- Followed my passion developing websites and script pages
- · Excelled in user experience and user interface work

## Interest

Playing Boardgames, Mountain Biking, Studying and learning new web development technologies, Playing video games